Qunliang Xing

37 Xueyuan Road Haidian District, Beijing, China ryanxingql@gmail.com https://ryanxingql.github.io

Introduction

Qunliang Xing is a Ph.D. student at Beihang University, advised by Changjiang Distinguished Professor Mai Xu. He obtained his BEng and Honors degrees at Beihang University in 2019. His research interests include image/video enhancement and coding. He has published two papers in IEEE TPAMI and one in ECCV, and one of them is top 1% highly cited according to the Essential Science Indicators (ESI). His papers have received over 300 citations. He has won two NTIRE championships. His open-source projects have received more than 600 stars. He was selected for the Tencent Rhino-bird Open-source Training Program. He is awarded the OpenMMLab Active Contributor. He serves as a reviewer for five IEEE transactions and conferences. He also excels in sports, having won second place in the Beihang 100m final and the Beihang soccer championship as the school team captain.

Education

Beihang University, Beijing, China	2019.9 – Present
Ph.D. student	School of Electronics and Information Engineering
Honors Ph.D. Student	Shen Yuan Honors College
Beihang University, Beijing, China	2015.9 – 2019.7
Bachelor of Engineering	School of Electronics and Information Engineering
Honors Bachelor	Shen Yuan Honors College

Publications

- [1] DAQE: Enhancing the Quality of Compressed Images by Exploiting the Inherent Characteristic of Defocus Quality Mai Xu, Xin Deng, Yichen Guo
- IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2023)
- [2] Progressive Training of A Two-Stage Framework for Video Restoration Qunliang Xing, Meisong Zheng, Minglang Qiao, Mai Xu, Lai Jiang, Huaida Liu, Ying Chen IEEE/CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops (2022) Technical report of our winning method in the NTIRE challenge.
- [3] DeepQTMT: A Deep Learning Approach for Fast QTMT-Based CU Partition of Intra-Mode VVC Tianyi Li, Mai Xu, Runzhi Tang, Ying Chen, Qunliang Xing IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (2021)
- [4] Early Exit Or Not: Resource-Efficient Blind Quality Enhancement for Compressed Images Qunliang Xing, Mai Xu, Tianyi Li, Zhenyu Guan European Conference on Computer Vision (2020)
- [5] MFQE 2.0: A New Approach for Multi-Frame Quality Enhancement on Compressed Video Qunliang Xing, Zhenyu Guan, Mai Xu, Ren Yang, Tie Liu, Zulin Wang IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2019) Highly cited paper (Top 1%) by Essential Science Indicators (ESI).

Work Experience

Research Intern 2021.12 – Present

Tao Technology, Alibaba Group

- Video quality enhancement for Taobao Live.
- Winning two championships and one runner-up in the NTIRE 2022 challenge.

Tencent Rhino-bird Open-Source Training Program

2021.7 - 2021.9

Tencent Open Source

• Selected as one of the 127 participants from over 1800 applicants.

Reviewer 2021.2 – Present

IEEE TIP/TMM/TCSVT/JAS/ICME

Research Intern 2018.12 – 2019.12

2012 Lab, Huawei

• Video quality enhancement for HW265 codec.

Honors and Awards

Beihang Excellent Academic Fund for PhD Candidates	
Beihang University (Rank 1/200+)	2023
Glarun Scholarship	
The 14TH Research Institute, CETC (Top 2/300+)	2022
Winner of the NTIRE challenge on video quality enhancement	
NTIRE	2022
Beihang Excellent Graduate	
Beihang University	2019
Beihang Outstanding/Merit Student	
Beihang University	2015/18/21/22
Shenzhen Merit Student	
Education Bureau of Shenzhen Municipality	2014